CURRICULUM VITAE

Proposed Position:	Material Engineer (International)	
Name of Staff:	Paul Wanyama	
Profession:	Civil Engineer	
Date of Birth:	30 th November 1987	
Nationality:	Kenyan	

Detail-oriented Civil Engineer with over 8 years of professional experience with a focus on transport infrastructure design, works implementation and project management. Proven history of guiding projects successfully while working for various UN agencies, private, and public organisations in the East African Region.

Education:

Institution (Date from - Date to):	Degree(s) or Diploma(s) obtained:	
University of Cape Town, South Africa (2015 - 2017)	Master of Science in Civil (Geotechnical) Engineering	
University of Nairobi (2007 - 2012)	Bachelor of Science in Civil Engineering	
Project Management Institute (PMI) (2020 – 2021) (On-going)	Project Management Professional (PMP) Certification	

Other Trainings:

- FIDIC Module 2: Claims and Dispute Resolution: 2017 Editions (FIDIC & ACEK) (Dec 2020);
- FIDIC Module 5: Advanced FIDIC (The Silver Book): 2017 Editions (FIDIC & ACEK) (Dec 2020);
- FIDIC Module 1: FIDIC Conditions of Contract for Construction (The Red Book): 2017 Editions (FIDIC & ACEK) - (Aug 2020);
- FIDIC Module 1: FIDIC Conditions of Contract for Construction (The Yellow Book): 2017 Editions (FIDIC & ACEK) (Aug 2020);
- Project Management Professional (PMP) Certification Prep Course (Iricon Training) (Oct 2020);
- Autodesk Infraworks Training at Centre for Innovative Technology (Citech) (Oct 2020);
- Introduction to Highway Design (KeNHA) (Feb 2020);
- AutoCAD Civil 3D Training at Centre for Innovative Technology (Citech) (Sep 2019);
- Pile Design and Construction University of Cape Town (Jun 2016);
- Soil Behaviour (Advanced Soil Mechanics) University of Stellenbosch (Apr 2015).

Kev Skills:

- New Pavement, Reseal and Rehabilitation Experience;
- Contract Administration and Project Management Experience Working with FIDIC Contracts;
- Contract and Tender Documentation;
- Engineering Procurement;
- Proficiency in AutoCAD And Civil 3D;
- Advanced Microsoft Google Suite Skills.

Professional Affiliations:

- International Society for Soil Mechanics & Geotechnical Engineering Member, 201500755;
- South African Institute of Civil Engineering (SAICE) Associate Member, 201500755;
- Institution of Engineers of Kenya (IEK) Corporate Member, M4784;
- Engineers Board of Kenya (EBK) Graduate Engineer, B7346.

Paul Wanyama Page 1/4

Employment Record Relevant To The Assignment:

Period	Organization and Title / Position	Country	Activities Performed
Apr 2021 -	United Nations Office for Project Services Somalia Country	Somalia	As mentioned below
to date	Office ((UNOPS SOCO)		
	Position: Materials Engineer		
Dec 2020 -	Kitui County Government	Kenya	As mentioned below
Feb 2021	Position: Materials Engineer		
Dec 2020 -	Machakos County Government	Kenya	As mentioned below
Feb 2021	Position: Materials Engineer		
Mar 2018 -	Norken International Ltd	Kenya	As mentioned below
Aug 2021	Position: Geotechnical/Materials Engineer		
Mar 2017 -	Nairobi City Water & Sewerage Company	Kenya	As mentioned below
Feb 2018	Position: Civil Engineer		
Oct 2016 -	Lilac Consulting Ltd	Ethiopia	As mentioned below
Feb 2016	Position: Geotechnical Engineer		
Jun 2012 -	Rural Focus Ltd	Kenya	As mentioned below
Jan 2015	Position: Civil Engineer		

Adequacy for the Assignment:

Reference to Prior Work / Assignments that Best Illustrate Capability to Handle the Assigned Tasks

Name of Project (P1): Technical Assistance for Somalia Urban Resilience Project II (SURP II) – Construction Supervision of Urban Roads in Garowe and Baidoa Municipalities, Somalia. <u>Project Length: 10 km; Funded By: World Bank.</u>

Year: Aug 2021 – to date; **Location:** Somalia; **Client:** United Nations Office for Project Services Somalia Country Office ((UNOPS SOCO); **Position Held:** Materials Engineer

Activities Performed: Responsible for advising the PIU with respect to the material submittals, approvals, sampling, testing etc. Working under the supervision of the Resident Engineer, assist the PIU for the quality control of the construction works being carried out by the Contractors ensuring that the works are in compliance to the approved design specifications. Undertake quality control, review of the material testing results and ensuring that the works carried out are in compliance to the design specifications.

Name of Project (P2): Technical Assistance for Somalia Crisis Recovery Project (SCRP) - Rehabilitation of Rural Gravel Roads and Health Facilities in Hirshabelle, South West and Jubaland States, Somalia. <u>Project Length:</u> 107 km; Funded By: World Bank.

Year: Apr 2021 – to date; **Location:** Somalia; **Client:** United Nations Office for Project Services Somalia Country Office ((UNOPS SOCO); **Position Held:** Materials Engineer

Activities Performed: Responsible for construction materials investigations, review and analysis of laboratory and field test results and recommending design parameters for pavement and foundation design. Responsible for preparation of pavement and foundation design reports. Provide technical guidance to design team realting to geotechnical and pavement design. Technology transfer and training of national staff.

Name of Project (P3): Detailed Design for Drainage and Road Works for Road (B7) Kaveta to Ginnery and Kunda Kindu Bus Park. <u>Project Length: 3 km; Project Cost: USD 2,450,980; Funded By: Kitui County Government.</u>

Year: Dec 2020 – Feb 2021; **Location:** Kenya; **Client:** Kitui County Government; **Position Held:** Materials Engineer **Activities Performed:** Successfully carried out materials scoping and investigations, supervision of materials testing, geotechnical analysis & design including pavement recommendations for the road and bus terminal. Preparation of the design report, project specifications and tender documentation.

Name of Project (P4): Detailed Engineering Design to Dual Carriageway of 16km Kyumvi (A109 Junction) - Machakos Section of (B62) Road. <u>Project Length: 16 km; Project Cost: USD 11,629,629; Funded By: Machakos County Government.</u>

Year: Dec 2020 – Feb 2021; Location: Kenya; Client: Machakos County Government; Position Held: Team Leader Cum Civil Engineer

Activities Performed: Successfully undertook materials investigations and pavement recommendations for the road including preparation of the design report, project specifications and tender documentation.

Name of Project (P6): Design Review and Construction Supervision of Dhogoye Bridge and Approach Roads on the Kisian – Usenge – Osieko (B10) Road. <u>Project Length: 5 km; Project Cost: USD 18,730,260; Funded By:</u> Government of Kenya.

Year: Oct 2020 – Aug 2021; Location: Kenya; Client: Kenya National Highways Authority (KeNHA); Position Held: Materials Engineer

Activities Performed: Review materials report and pavement design; checking the quality of construction materials; Review of quality assurance plan; materials testing/material sites approval; checking the quality of construction materials; checking contractor's compliance with specifications and workmanship; checking tests on completion/final

Paul Wanyama Page 2/4

acceptance tests; technology transfer and training of client's counterpart staff. Co-ordinating and directing team of professionals like engineers, inspectors, surveyors and laboratory technicians.

Name of Project (P7): Design Review and Construction Supervision for the Improvement of Beletweyne Airport Runway. <u>Project Length: 2.2 km; Project Cost: USD 1,872,345; Funded By: United Nations Support Office in Somalia (UNSOS).</u>

Year: Aug 2019 – Apr 2021; **Location:** Somalia; **Client**: United Nations Support Office in Somalia (UNSOS); **Position Held:** Materials Engineer

Activities Performed: Provided overall leadership during pre-construction studies, construction and post-construction consultancy services for the rehabilitation of the existing 2.2 km long and 32 m wide runway. The runway status was upgraded by use of 200mm cement stabilised lateritic gravel and a provision for stage construction of an asphaltic surfacing. Review design; prepare health, safety, security and environment plan in line with aviation safety procedures. overseeing operational quality assurance and quality control processes; verification of measurements, progress monitoring and reporting, review of work programmes and ensure compliance with specifications, maintaining construction documents including drawings, monthly technical reports and site meeting minutes. Co-ordinating and directing team of professionals like engineers, inspectors, surveyors and laboratory technicians. Responsible for management of project resources.

Name of Project (P8): Detailed Engineering Design of Naivasha Road and Kikuyu Road. <u>Project Length: 20 km;</u> Project Cost: USD 35,850,300; Funded By: Government of Kenya.

Year: Aug 2020 – Feb 2021; **Location:** Kenya; **Client:** Kenya Urban Roads Authority (KURA); **Position Held:** Materials Engineer

Activities Performed: Review of design standards, materials investigations, testing and recommending design parameters, design of pavement and report the findings. Technology transfer and training of client's counterpart staff.

Name of Project (P9): Detailed Engineering Design of Kiambu – Ngewa – Kibichoi - Thika Road. <u>Project Length:</u> 52 km; Project Cost: USD 157,198,631; Funded By: Government of Kenya.

Year: Dec 2018 – Jul 2020; **Location:** Kenya; **Client:** Kenya National Highways Authority (KeNHA); **Position Held:** Materials Engineer

Activities Performed: Review of design standards, materials investigations, testing and recommending design parameters, design of pavement and report the findings. Geotechnical investigation scoping and specifications, general project management, review of the geotechnical reports and recommendation of design parameters for the bridge foundations. Preparation of drawings, engineer's cost estimates, and tender documentation, and technology transfer and training of client's counterpart staff.

Name of Project (P10): Detailed Engineering Design of Detailed Engineering Design of Isiolo - Lokichar Road Project. Project Length: 419 km; Project Cost: USD 554,954,485; Funded By: African Development Bank (AfDB) Year: Mar 2018 – Jun 2020; Location: Kenya; Client: Kenya National Highways Authority (KeNHA); Position Held: Materials Engineer

Activities Performed: Construction materials investigations, sampling and testing. Recommending design parameters, design of pavement and report the findings. Geotechnical investigation scoping and specifications, general project management, review of the geotechnical reports and recommendation of design parameters for the bridge foundations. Preparation engineer's cost estimates, tender documentation and technology transfer and training of client's counterpart staff.

Name of Project (P11): Design Review and Construction |Supervison of 11 No. Bridges on Lot 2: Upgrading of Lokitaung Junction – Kalobeiyei River (A1) Road. <u>Project Length: 80 km; Project Value: USD 138,440; Funded By: World Bank</u>

Year: Mar 2019 – Jun 2019; **Location:** Kenya; **Client:** Chongqing International Construction Corporation (CICO); **Position Held:** Geotechnical Engineer

Activities Performed: Detailed geotechnical investigations scoping, general project management, review of the geotechnical reports and foundation recommendations.

Name of Project (P12): Somalia - Urban Resilience Project II (SURP II) - Detailed Engineering Designs for the Priority Urban Roads in Kismayo and Baidoa, Somalia. <u>Project Length: 50 km; Project Cost: USD 21,000,000; Funded By: World Bank</u>

Year: May 2019 – May 2020; Location: Somalia; Client: United Nations Office for Project Services Somalia Country Office ((UNOPS SOCO); Position Held: Geotechnical Engineer

Activities Performed: Construction materials investigations, sampling and testing. Recommending design parameters, design of pavement and report the findings. Technology transfer and training of client's counterpart staff.

Name of Project (P13): Detailed Engineering Design of Mombasa – Mtwapa – Kwa Kadzengo – Kilifi. <u>Project Length: 55 km; Project Value: USD 1,200,800; Funded By: African Development Bank (AfDB)</u>

Year: Oct 2018 – Mar 2019; **Location:** Kenya; **Client:** Kenya National Highways Authority (KeNHA); **Position Held:** Materials Engineer

Activities Performed: Construction materials investigations, sampling and testing. Recommending design parameters, design of pavement and report the findings. Geotechnical investigation scoping and specifications, general project management, review of the geotechnical reports and recommendation of design parameters for the bridge foundations. Preparation engineer's cost estimates, tender documentation and technology transfer and training of client's counterpart staff.

Paul Wanyama Page 3/4

Name of Project (P14): Construction Supervision of the Proposed Karen Plains Water Improvement and Extension Works. <u>Project Length: 8.7 km; Project Cost: USD 416,673; Funded By: Government of Kenya</u>

Year: Mar 2017 – Feb 2018; Location: Kenya; Client: Nairobi City Water & Sewerage Company Limited; Position Held: Civil Engineer

Activities Performed: Construction supervision, pressure testing and water quality testing, attend site inspection and site meetings, report writing.

Name of Project (P15): Construction Supervision of Relocation of Water Supply and Sewer Infrastructure During Dualling of Ngong Road - Phase II and III. <u>Project Length: 15 km; Project Cost: USD 7,500,000; Funded By: Government of Kenya</u>

Year: Mar 2017 – Feb 2018; **Location:** Kenya; **Client:** Kenya Urban Roads Authority (KURA); **Position Held:** Civil Engineer

Activities Performed: Construction supervision; issuance of site instructions; verification of quality of executed works and materials used; verification of measurements and issuance of interim payment certificates; monitoring contractor's work progress, preparation of progress reports and advising the engineer accordingly, analysis of any claims submitted by the contractor; technology transfer and training of client's staff; pressure testing and water quality testing, attend site inspection and site meetings, and report writing.

Name of Project (P16): Proposed Bahir Dar – Kombolcha – Woldiya Power Transmission Line. <u>Project Cost:</u> USD 800,000; Funded By: African Development Bank (AfDB)

Year: Oct 2016 – Feb 2017; **Location:** Ethiopia; **Client:** TATA/ Ethiopian Electric Power Corporation; **Position Held:** Geotechnical Engineer

Activities Performed: Detailed geotechnical investigations scoping, general project management, design and review of the geotechnical reports and foundation recommendations at 800 tower locations. Geotechnical analysis, design and report writing.

Name of Project (P17): Construction Supervision of Koibatek Community Water Project. <u>Project Cost: USD</u> 122,199; Funded By: World Bank

Year: Mar 2017 – Feb 2018; **Location:** Kenya; **Client:** Koibatek Community Water Project; **Position Held:** Civil Engineer

Activities Performed: Contract administration, project management and construction supervision of the water supply reticulation system. Oversee the quality control and quality assurance aspects during construction; work schedule control works measurements and budget control; progress monitoring and reporting; and attending site meetings.

Paul Wanyama Page 4/4